<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<div id="root">
    <h1>Getting here</h1>

    <section xml:id="travel-to-victoria">
        <h2>Getting Here: Travel to Victoria</h2>
        <p>
            The University of Victoria is located on the traditional lands of the Songhees, Esquimalt and WSÁNEĆ peoples, whose historical relationships with the land continue to this day. Specifically, it is located on the ancestral land of the Lekwungen family group, Checkonien and Sungayka village. According to
            <a href="https://www.uvic.ca/services/indigenous/">Cheryl Bryce</a>
            of the Songhees Nation, the site “was known for camas harvesting, trading and cultural and spiritual practices.”</p>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="by-air">
        <h2>Getting Here: By Air</h2>
        <p><a
                href="https://www.victoriaairport.com/"
                >Victoria International Airport</a> (YYJ) is located approximately 30 minutes from the University of Victoria. Flights arrive daily from across Canada, the US, and Europe. In general, it is most cost efficient and convenient to fly into Victoria (rather than Vancouver or Seattle), unless you are coming from those areas or have other reasons to stop there during your trip.</p>
        <p>For getting to and from the airport, we recommend the <a
                href="https://yyjairportshuttle.com/"
                >YYJ Airport Shuttle</a>; you may need to call and confirm a shuttle spot or time. The cost is $25 CAD for one adult; less if you are traveling in a group of two or more. Specific fares and schedules can be found on their website. A taxi to downtown Victoria hotels from the airport will cost approximately $60 CAD.</p>
        <p>Float plane service is available from Vancouver (<a href="https://www.harbourair.com/">Harbour Air</a>) and Seattle (<a
                href="https://www.kenmoreair.com/"
                >Kenmore Air</a>) to Victoria&apos;s Inner Harbour. Helicopter service between Vancouver and Victoria&apos;s downtown Inner Harbour is also available (<a
                href="https://helijet.com/"
                >HeliJet</a>).</p>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="by-ground">
        <h2>Getting Here: By Ground</h2>
        <p>From Vancouver: <a
                href="https://www.pacificcoach.com/"
                >Pacific Coach</a> offers a bus service between downtown Vancouver, Vancouver Airport and downtown Victoria 3 times/day. This trip involves taking the ferry from Tsawwassen on the mainland to Swartz Bay on Vancouver Island. Once your bus has driven on to the ferry, you are free to wander the ship, get a snack and relax.</p>
        <p><a href="https://bctransit.com/victoria/">BC Transit</a> provides affordable and convenient bus transportation throughout Victoria.</p>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="by-sea">
        <h2>Getting Here: By Sea</h2>
        <p>There are regular ferries from Vancouver and Seattle to Victoria. For more information, visit <a href="https://www.bcferries.com/">BC Ferries</a> or <a
                href="https://www.clippervacations.com/"
                >Clipper Ferry</a>. The ferry from Vancouver docks in Swartz Bay, approximately 40 minutes by ground travel from the University or downtown. The Clipper Ferry from Seattle arrives at the Inner Harbour downtown, about 20 minutes by ground from the University.</p>
    </section>
</div>